Jermaine varnicker



jvarnicker@yahoo.com



0780323334



linkedin.com/in/jermaine-varnicker-315a8794



https://jermainev.github.io/

Summary

Experienced Fraud Analyst with a demonstrated history of working in the banking industry. Skilled in Data Wrangling, Statistical Data Analysis, Big Data Analytics, Data Science, and Data Visualization, Data modelling, T-SQL. Strong finance professional with a Specialization focused in Data science from CTU Training Solutions.

For an in-depth view of my skills please visit my portfolio at the below link: https://github.com/JermaineV

Experience

Fraud Analyst

FNB South Africa

Jan 2011 - Feb 2016 (5 years 2 months)

- -Fraud Detection, Analyzing fraud via AI and visa online system
- -Meeting of targets to contact customers with regards to possible fraud.
- -Opening of new fraud cases for Debit and cheque card fraud.
- -Updating customer's fraud cases on customer profile.
- -Following up on existing cases Card cancellations.
- -Receive calls from internal & external customers.
- -Confirmations of fraudulent transactions from other banks
- -Customer Service
- -Hot listing of Cards and send affidavits to customer.

Reference: Nirvana Ramboth (HR manager)

Tell: 087 311 7557

Dispute Analyst

FNB South Africa

Feb 2016 - Present (5 years 6 months +)

- -Charge Backs- Accurate processing of charge backs in line with applicable codes which comply with the appropriate payment system (e.g. Visa and MasterCard) rules.
- -Fraud Document Compilation and Supply- Timely, accurate checking and comprehensive compilation and supply of fraud related documentation in the required format to support efforts in addressing identified fraud events.
- -Service Delivery- Deliver exceptional service that exceeds customers' expectations through proactive, innovative and appropriate solutions.
- -Arbitration- Execute activities for arbitration of cases by preparing required information, which includes controlled sharing of customer information between banks, engaging with various stakeholders to validate any transactions.
- -Case Recording and Monitoring- Recording and/or monitoring of fraud cases in internal and external databases.
- -Fraud Information- Timely and accurate recording and checking of fraud related information to disseminate to relevant stakeholders.

- -Fraud Process, Rules and System Compliance- Execute fraud administration duties in line with required rules, processes and using available systems. Ensure that activities are executed in a timely manner and accuracy.
- -Operational Losses- Contribute to the reduction in operational losses by providing efficient administrative support to the fraud team.
- -Recoveries- Execute recovery activities in line with applicable standards and laws to maximize recoveries for the Bank.
- -Reporting Fraud Support- Compile and communicate accurate and timely reports on fraud according to area of focus.

Reference: Ntombi Lebuso (manager)

Tell: 087 311 2377



📘 IT Field Technician

JNT Computers (PTY) Ltd

Jun 2015 - Apr 2016 (11 months)

- -Performing backups and installing hardware
- -Installing printers and administering user accounts
- -Ensuring adherence to quality standards in the organization
- -Troubleshooting and resolving technical errors
- -Attending to ad-hoc tasks and requests
- -Maintaining of technological trends and developments
- -Appointed as a computer service and maintenance technician
- -Performing software installations and upgrades
- -Installing, configuring and providing support on network connections
- -Assisting with ad-hoc technical assignments as required

Reference: Jimmy Jordaan (Manager)

061 425 6760

Education



Silver Oaks Secondary School

High School Diploma, High School Diploma

2002 - 2006

CTU Training Solutions

National Certificate: Information Technology (Systems Development), Data science 2020 - 2021

Results:

Module 1: Principles of Program Design

89.09%

Module 2: Relational Database Design

93.67%

Module 3: Database Programming

92.72%

```
Module 4: Introduction to Statistics 97.6%
```

Module 5: Introduction to data science 94.06%

Module 6: Big Data Analysis 98.21%

Module 7: Python 96.36%

Total 94.49%

Licenses & Certifications

Exam 761: Querying Data with Transact-SQL - Microsoft

Skills

Big Data • Machine Learning • Transact-SQL (T-SQL) • Data Science • Statistical Data Analysis • Python (Programming Language) • Predictive Analytics • Data Wrangling • Microsoft Power BI • Database Design